pipingrock.com 2019-12-05

# Privacy Policy | Piping Rock Health Products

Last modified May 24, 2018

ATTENTION: PLEASE READ CAREFULLY THIS PRIVACY POLICY (“PRIVACY POLICY”), WHICH IS PART OF THE PIPING ROCK TERMS OF USE, BEFORE YOU ACCESS, DOWNLOAD, OR OTHERWISE USE OUR WEBSITE, OTHER PARTIES’ WEBSITES, MOBILE APPLICATIONS OR ANY ELECTRONIC SERVICE (COLLECTIVELY, THE “SERVICE”).

The Service is operated by Piping Rock Health Products, LLC, 2120 Smithtown Ave, Ronkonkoma, NY 11779 (“We” or “Piping Rock”). At Piping Rock, we care deeply about your privacy rights. We are fully committed to being transparent about our privacy practices, including how we treat your personal information. This Privacy Policy describes the information collected through Your use of the Service, how We use it, how We share it, how We protect it, and the choices You can make about Your information.

ATTENTION: PLEASE READ OUR PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THE SERVICE. USING THE SERVICE INDICATES THAT YOU ACCEPT AND AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY IN FULL. IF YOU DO NOT ACCEPT THIS PRIVACY POLICY, DO NOT USE THE SERVICE. You acknowledge (a) that You have read and understood this Privacy Policy; and (b) this Privacy Policy shall have the same force and effect as a signed agreement.

Unless explicitly stated otherwise, any new features that augment or enhance the current Service shall be subject to this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy is part of the Piping Rock Terms of Use (TOU). Any terms defined in the TOU shall have the same meaning in this Privacy Policy.

We will update this page to reflect any changes to this Privacy Policy. Please review the Privacy Policy each time You use the Service. BY USING THE SERVICE, YOU AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THE MOST RECENT VERSION OF THE PRIVACY POLICY.

## I. Information We Receive or Collect

We receive or collect information from You when You use the Service, contact or interact with us, sign up for our newsletter or other mailing list, and voluntarily provide us with Your feedback, comments and other content in connection with using the Service.

As part of your access to and use of the Service, we may receive and collect: Your name, contact information including email address, telephone number, address, payment information, order history, and any other information you voluntarily provide on the Service.

When You contact us, We may collect: Your name, contact information including email address, telephone number, and any other information that You voluntarily provide to us.

When You access and use the Service, we automatically collect information regarding You and Your device, including Your device’s Internet Protocol address, the domain name of Your Internet service provider, Your location, Your mobile device information (e.g. device model and operating system version), your page visits, your social sharing activity, and other aggregated information that, on its own, cannot be used to specifically identify You. Additional information collected is described in the Analytics and Cookies sections below.

We may collect information about You from third party sources. The Service provides links to our Facebook, Twitter, and Pinterest pages. If You connect with these websites through the Service, We may receive personal information about You.

We may combine all of the information we collect from or about You and use it in the manner described in this Privacy Policy.

## II. How We Use Your Information

We use the information that We collect for several purposes, including:

  * \- The purposes for which You provided it;
  * \- To provide information and services to You;
  * \- To process and respond to Your inquiries and comments;
  *  
  * \- To send You information about Your relationship with us or about new projects or other information that we think You may find interesting;
  *  
  * \- To contact You for market research purposes and to use this information to customize the Service according to Your interests;
  *  
  * \- To administer, operate, and improve the Service or to further the mission of Piping Rock;
  *  
  * \- To personalize and enhance Your experience using the Service;
  *  
  * \- To send periodic emails. If You choose, the email address You provide may be used to send You occasional news, updates, related product or service information, etc. Note: If at any time You would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, We include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email;
  *  
  * \- To generate and review reports and data about our user base and Service usage patterns;
  *  
  * \- To analyze the accuracy, effectiveness, usability or popularity of the Service;
  *  
  * \- To compile aggregate data for internal and external business purposes;
  *  
  * \- To prevent fraud and abuse of the Service and to otherwise protect users and visitors and our business;
  *  
  * \- To assist law enforcement and respond to subpoenas;
  *  
  * \- To perform other business activities as needed, or as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy; and
  *  
  * \- As explained elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, personal information We collect may be processed by our partners in providing services related to the Service (such as administration services, technical services relating to the maintenance, servicing, and upgrading of software, hosting services, customer service, data migration services, payment processing services and analytical services, among others).
  *  

## III. Legal Bases for Using Personal Information

### Performance of a contract

The use of your personal information may be necessary to perform the agreement you have with us to provide products and services. For example, to complete your purchase, to register and maintain your account, to help with delivery issues, to handle returns, and to respond to your requests.

### Legitimate interests

We may use your personal information for our legitimate interests. For example, We rely on our legitimate interest to analyze and improve our Services and the content on our website, to send you notifications about our Services, or to use your personal information for administrative, fraud detection, or legal purposes.

### Consent

Prior to accessing this site and providing your Personal Data, You provided Your informed consent to the collection and use of said Personal Data. You are free to withdraw your consent at any time, subject to the "Your Choices Regarding Your Information" section below and the preceding Legal Bases for Using Personal Information in this Section.

## IV. How Your Information is Disclosed

Information may be disclosed to third parties in accordance with our Privacy Policy. Please note that a user may choose not to share certain information as described in Your Choices Regarding Your Information below.

_A. Third Party Service Providers and Business Partners._ We may use third party service providers and business partners to perform functions in connection with the Service, such as email marketing, site analytics, social sharing, relationship management, functions related to analyzing and improving the Service usefulness, reliability, user experience, operation, storing data, and as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. Specifically, our third party providers may be assisting us with verification of your shipping address, content delivery, monitoring inventory levels, product ratings and reviews, providing credit and debit card payment processing and order fulfillment and shipment processing, email marketing, fraud prevention and order placements, facilitating communications for order fulfillment, email transmission for multi-factor verification, creation of shopping feeds for our users, and communicate with users regarding orders and other customer service inquiries. The identity of certain of these service providers is confidential. We also may share Your personal information with these providers and partners for their direct marketing and promotional purposes, so they can provide services to You. Our third party service providers, and their use of your information, by their very nature continue to evolve. We may add or substitute these providers without any notice to you.

Strictly by way of generic example, our thirds party providers include the following:

  * \- Twitter. By clicking on the Twitter button on the Service, You will automatically be transported to the official Twitter feed of Piping Rock, @PipingRock, https://twitter.com/Piping_Rock.
  * \- Facebook. By clicking on the Facebook button on the Service, You will be automatically transported to the official Facebook Page for Piping Rock, https://www.facebook.com/PipingRock. Piping Rock allows users to comment on blog posts using the Facebook Comments Plugin and in doing so, Piping Rock may have access to personal information about You. For more information on the Facebook Comments Plugin, [please visit.](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/comments)
  * \- Pinterest. By clicking on the Pinterest button on the Service, You will be automatically transported to the official Pinterest profile for Piping Rock, https://www.pinterest.com/PipingRock/.
  * \- PayPal. We use PayPal to process payments. PayPal may collect information from users including name, physical address, IP address, device information, phone number, financial account information, details including gender, and other demographic information. For more information, please visit [PayPal's privacy policy.](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full)

_B. Business Changes._ If We become involved in a merger, acquisition, sale of assets, joint venture, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, liquidation, dissolution, or other transaction or if the ownership of all or substantially all of our business otherwise changes, We may transfer Your information to a third party or parties in connection therewith.

_C. Affiliates._ We may also share Your information with our affiliates for purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy. Our affiliates will be required to maintain that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

_D. Investigations and Law._ We may disclose information about You to third parties if We believe that such disclosure is necessary to:

  * \- Comply with the law or guidance and cooperate with government or law enforcement officials or private parties;
  * \- Investigate, prevent or take action regarding suspected illegal activities, suspected fraud, the rights, reputation, safety, and property of us, users or others, or violations of our policies or other agreements with us;
  * \- Respond to claims and legal process (for example, subpoenas); and/or
  * \- Protect against legal liability.

_E. Aggregated Information._ We may share aggregated information relating to users of the Service with affiliated or unaffiliated third parties. This aggregated information does not contain personal information about any user.

_F. Analytics._ We use third-party analytics tools to better understand who is using the Service and how people are using it. These tools may use cookies and other technologies to collect information about Your use of the Service and Your preferences and activities. These tools collect information sent by Your device or the Service and other information that assists us in improving the Service. This information may be used to analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, and better understand Your online activity, among other things.

By way of a reasonably representative example only, we use Google Analytics to better understand who is using the Service and how people are using it. Google Analytics uses cookies to collect and store information such as Service pages visited, places where users click, time spent on each Service page, Internet Protocol address, type of operating system used, location-based data, device ID, search history, gender, age, and phone number. We use this information to improve the Service and as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. Please [click here](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/) for information about how Google Analytics uses this information, and [click here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) for information about the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on. Google may track your activity over time and across websites.

_G. Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies_

We, along with third parties, use cookies, local storage objects, Web beacons and other technologies. These technologies are used for tracking, analytics and personalization and optimization of the Service.

Cookies are small files that are transferred to and stored on Your computer through Your Web browser (if You allow it) that enable the website’s or service provider’s system to recognize Your browser and capture and remember certain information. You can instruct Your browser to stop accepting cookies. But if You do not accept cookies, You may not be able to use all portions of all functionality of the Service.

  * \- Persistent cookies remain on the visitor’s computer after the browser has been closed.
  * \- Session cookies exist only during a visitor’s online session and disappear from the visitor’s computer when they close the browser software.

Flash cookies (also known as local shared objects) are data files that can be created on your computer by the websites you visit and are a way for websites to store information for later use. Flash cookies are stored in different parts of your computer from ordinary browser cookies. You can disable the storage of flash cookies. For additional information about managing and disabling flash cookies, please [visit.](http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html)

Web beacons are small strings of code that provide a method for delivering a graphic image on a Web page or in an email message for the purpose of transferring data. You can disable the ability of Web beacons to capture information by blocking cookies.

We use cookies and other tracking technologies on the website to help us understand and save Your preferences and interests so We can personalize Your future visits and compile aggregate data about website traffic and website interaction so that We can offer better website experiences and tools in the future.

Some of our business partners, such as our analytics providers, advertising networks, social sharing provider, and social media connections, also use cookies and other tracking technologies on our website, some of which may track users across websites and over time. Given the nature of third party services, they are constantly evolving and if you have any questions concerning the use or policies of those third parties, we encourage you to consult their Privacy Policies and Terms of Use directly.

## V. Security

We implement a variety of security measures to protect the safety of Your personal information when You enter, submit, or access Your personal information.

While We take reasonable measures to protect the information You submit via the Service against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure, or modification, We cannot guarantee its absolute security. No Internet, email, or mobile application transmission is ever fully secure or error free. Email or other messages sent through the Service may not be secure. You should use caution whenever submitting information through the Service and take special care in deciding with which information You provide us.

We cannot guarantee that transmissions of Your personal information will be fully secure and that third parties will never be able to defeat our security measures or the security measures of our partners. WE ASSUME NO LIABILITY FOR DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION DUE TO TRANSMISSION ERRORS, THIRD PARTY ACCESS, OR CAUSES BEYOND OUR CONTROL.

Any information collected through the Service is stored and processed in the United States. If you use our Service outside of the United States, you consent to have your data transferred to the United States.

## VI. Data Retention Policy, Managing Your Information

We will retain Your information for as long as You use the Service and for a reasonable time thereafter. Piping Rock is a regulated entity and must retain order records under United States Food and Drug Administration regulations. We may maintain anonymized or aggregated data, including usage data, for analytics purposes. We may retain and use Your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and/or for the period required by laws in applicable jurisdictions. Please note that some or all of the information We have collected may be required for the Service to function properly. Our current policy is to maintain order records for two (2) years to allow us to protect and meet Our legal and policy requirements, rights, and responsibilities.

## VII. Links to Other Websites or Applications

This Privacy Policy applies only to the Service. The Service may contain links to other websites or apps or may forward users to other websites or apps that We may not own or operate and to which this Privacy Policy does not apply. The links from the Service do not imply that We endorse or have reviewed these websites or apps. The policies and procedures We describe here do not apply to these websites or apps. We neither can control nor are responsible for the privacy practices or content of these websites or apps. We suggest contacting these websites or app providers directly for information on their privacy policies. Nonetheless, We seek to protect the integrity of our Service, and welcome any feedback about these linked websites and mobile applications.

## VIII. Your Choices Regarding Your Information

You have choices regarding the use of information by the Service. We respect Your privacy rights and provide You with reasonable access to the Personal Data that You may have provided through Your use of the Services. You may update, correct, or delete Your account information and preferences at any time by accessing Your account settings page on the Service. Please note that while any changes You make will be reflected in active user databases instantly or within a reasonable period of time, We may retain all information You submit for backups, archiving, prevention of fraud and abuse, analytics, satisfaction of legal obligations, or where We otherwise reasonably believe that we have a legitimate reason to do so.

You may decline to share certain Personal Data with us, in which case we may not be able to provide to You some of the features and functionality of the Service.

EU Data Subjects may, at any time, object to the processing of your Personal Data, on legitimate grounds, except if otherwise permitted by applicable law, or lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

## IX. EU Residents Rights to Access, Transfer or Delete Personal Information, or Withdraw Consent to Collection or Processing

If You are an EU Data Subject and wish to access, transfer or delete any Personal Data that We hold about You, or withdraw Your consent to collection or processing Your data to request that We delete any information about You that We have obtained, You can do so by emailing us at [data-privacy@pipingrock.com](mailto:data-privacy@pipingrock.com?subject=EU%20Residents%20Rights) and stating your request. With respect to requests to delete Your personal data, We will delete or block any ability to access any reference to You in our database, except for information required to be retained as provided for in our Privacy Policy, and consistent with our legal requirements and internal data retention policies, as described above. This deletion is permanent and Your account cannot be reinstated. Changing Your Information – To change Your information, please contact us at [customerservice@pipingrock.com](mailto:customerservice@pipingrock.com).

## X. Information Collected From Other Websites and Mobile Applications and Do Not Track Policy

Your browser or device may offer You a “Do Not Track” option, which allows You to signal to operators of websites, web applications, mobile applications and services (including behavioral advertising services) that You do not wish such operators to track certain of Your online activities over time and/or across different websites or applications. Our Service does not support Do Not Track requests at this time, which means that We or our analytics providers or other third parties with which We are working may collect information about Your online activity both during and after Your use of the Service.

## XI. Children

Our Service is not intended for children under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly collect personal information from an individual under age 13. If You are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal information through the Service. If You have reason to believe that We may have accidentally received personal information from an individual under age 13, please contact us immediately at [customerservice@pipingrock.com](mailto:customerservice@pipingrock.com).

## XII. Changes to Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time without prior notice. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically, and especially before You provide any information. This Privacy Policy was made effective on the date indicated above.

## XIII. How to Contact Us

Please feel free to contact us by email at [customerservice@pipingrock.com](mailto:customerservice@pipingrock.com) or by writing us at Piping Rock Health Products, LLC, 2120 Smithtown Ave, Ronkonkoma, NY 11779, if You have any questions about this Privacy Policy.

## XIV. Your California Privacy Rights

Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code permits California residents to request from a business, with whom the California resident has an established business relationship, certain information about the types of personal information the business has shared with third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes and the names and addresses of the third parties with whom the business has shared such information during the immediately preceding calendar year. You may make one request each year by emailing us at [customerservice@pipingrock.com](mailto:customerservice@pipingrock.com) or by writing us at Piping Rock Health Products, LLC, 2120 Smithtown Ave, Ronkonkoma, NY 11779.
